Guide to the NYU Abu Dhabi Memory Project Collection AD.RG.023
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Interviews with NYUAD Community Members [during Covid], Spring 2020 - Summer 2022
  - Interview session with Renee Dugan, Suparna Mathur (Community Outreach) and Lauren Kata (01:23:23), 19 Sept 2021; ADRG023_069 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_069)
    In this interview, the members reflect on their journey and roles at NYU Abu Dhabi from its early days, and their experiences of building connections with a wider community/organizations. Renee shares her journey at NYUAD from its early days, starting as a Director of Admissions to founding Director of Community Outreach and current role as Associate Dean of Students and Director of Student Life. Similarly, Director of Community Outreach, Suparna, also shares about her experience working with NYUAD. Both reflect on their contributions and initiations in building a broad foundational network of NYUAD, approaching numerous academic and social groups/organizations and establishing NYUAD as a center for collaboration, especially regarding meaningful and sustainable engagement for students. Suparna recalls how Community Outreach worked hard to include a variety of volunteering opportunities and increasing their accessibility for students and staff. The two also shed light on how Community Outreach works collaboratively to prepare, plan, and execute programs keeping in mind the core mission of NYUAD and adding value to student life.
  - Interview session with Theresa Powell (HR) and Lauren Kata (01:20:45), 17 October 2021; ADRG023_070 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_070)
    Video-recorded session with Theresa Powell, Deputy Chief for People and Performance at NYU Abu Dhabi, on Sunday, October 17th, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, Theresa shares about her journey to NYUAD, her contributions and experiences while working in the HR Office. She talks about her first impression of Abu Dhabi, the culture, people and climate, which are completely different from her previous workplaces back in London. She vividly recalls her first day at the Downtown campus and the warm welcome she received. She has fun memories of shifting to the Saadiyat campus and adjusting to new campus life. Theresa mentions the work she has accomplished, like the Saadiyat Social, hosting onboarding cultural orientation to the new staff and faculty, and employee service and recognition parties. Engaging, volunteering, and communicating with students is what excites her. Theresa, at the end, says she is very proud and happy for being part of NYUAD.
  - Interview session with Dustin Harris (Public Affairs) and Lauren Kata (01:15:20), 17 November 2021; ADRG023_071 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_071)
    Video-recorded session with Dustin Harris, Senior Designer in the Public Affairs and Communication Team at NYU Abu Dhabi, on Wednesday, November 17th, 2021 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections at NYUAD. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, Dustin shares about his journey to NYUAD, his contributions and experiences while working as a Senior Designer in the Public Affairs and Communication Department. He shares how he first heard about NYUAD and his earliest impressions of Abu Dhabi. He speaks about his initial roles and responsibilities of collaborating, helping and setting expectations of his team regarding designing and branding of the university at a crucial transitional phase of a growing global institution. Dustin outlines his work which has ranged from maintaining public websites, ad campaigns, to hosting large events like Commencement ceremonies, and Marhaba. He fondly remembers the entire creative work process, put together resulting in the creation of a meaningful logo and tagline for the 10th Year Anniversary celebration.
  - Interview session with Tegan McDuffie (Theater, A&H) and Lauren Kata (01:35:14), 09 January 2022; ADRG023_072 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_072)
    Video-recorded session with Tegan Mc Duffie, Instructor of Project and Stage Management, recorded on January 9, 2022 and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Archivist and Assistant Academic Librarian. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, Tegan describes how she got invited to be a stage manager for a production at NYUAD, which eventually led her to a full-time job. She explains her first impressions of Abu Dhabi, and then working at NYU Abu Dhabi on productions such as RealAD, but she also emphasizes best practices as an instructor and considerations around the cultural context of the country. She touches upon the important aspects of dealing with various equipment and how students have utilized equipment in their Capstone pieces. Tegan discusses NYUAD's signature theater programs and finally reflects on her personal experience and growth period while at NYUAD.
  - Interview session with John Pine (Alumni Relations) and Lauren Kata (01:07:44), 24 January 2022; ADRG023_073 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_073)
    Video-recorded session, with John Pine, Director of Alumni Relations and Annual Giving at NYU Abu Dhabi, recorded on Monday, January 24, 2022, and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Librarian for Archives and Special Collections, NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, John Pine, talks about his experience at NYU Abu Dhabi as Director of Alumni Relations and Annual Giving between 2018 and 2022. Prior to joining NYUAD, Pine served as Director of Outreach Programs at the NYU office in New York for five years. He shares that he was impressed by the diverse multicultural environment offered at NYU Abu Dhabi. As a Director of Alumni Relations, he created a strategic plan for improving alumni engagement with a focus on 4 key areas: 1) alumni-to-alumni engagement through traditional methods (e.g., events, regional programs, career support); 2) alumni-to-student support via mentorship and advising; 3) communications and marketing (sharing alumni stories in different media, e.g. social media, website); 4) philanthropy. Pine also shares his memories from organizing reunion dinners for alumni to sharing alumni stories in different mediums, such as Beyond Saadiyat and a podcast in collaboration with the Career Development Center.
  - Interview session with Shamoon Zamir and Lauren Kata (01:49:03), 18 February 2022; ADRG023_074 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_074)
    [summary in process]
  - Interview session with Bryan Waterman and Lauren Kata (Part 1) (01:59:00), 31 May 2022; ADRG023_075 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_075)
    This is Session 1 of a two-session set of interviews conducted as part of Bryan Waterman's exiting NYUAD.
    Note: there are two recordings in this first session; the first recording is the bulk of the interview, and then a 4-minute epilogue was added to describe Bryan's Zoom background, which is an image of artwork that was special to him.
  - Interview session with Deborah Williams and Lauren Kata (01:49:23), 06 September 2022; ADRG023_076 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_076)
    Video-recorded session with Deborah William - Clinical Full Professor at the School of Liberal Studies of New York University and facilitated by Lauren Kata - Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this interview, NYU affiliated faculty member Deborah Williams of the Literature and Creative Writing program delves into various aspects of her experience at NYU Abu Dhabi since the days of the Downtown campus. She highlighs student engagement and the evolution of the curriculum over time, as well as her involvement in initiating literary journals and community reading events. Williams also reflects on the residential aspect of campus life, sharing personal anecdotes about living accommodations and community dynamics. Additionally, she addresses pressing issues such as diversity, labor rights, and the quality of discourse within the institution, emphasizing the need for meaningful conversations and systemic change. Despite facing institutional challenges, Williams expresses appreciation for the extraordinary students and colleagues she has encountered at NYU Abu Dhabi.
  - Interview session with Justin Stearns (Faculty Labor Committee) and Lauren Kata (01:47:36), 21 June 2022; ADRG023_081 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_081)
  - Interview session with Bryan Waterman and Lauren Kata (Part 2) (01:20:54), 23 June 2022; ADRG023_082 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_082)
  - Interview session with Sebastian Grube and Lauren Kata (01:06:51), 24 June 2022; ADRG023_083 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_083)
    Video-recorded session, with Sebastian Grube, former Community Engagement and Marketing Officer at NYU Abu Dhabi Art Gallery, recorded on Friday, June 24, 2022, and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Librarian for Archives and Special Collections, NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    In this session, Sebastian Grube shares his experiences at NYU Abu Dhabi as a member of the Class of 2018 and a former Community Engagement and Marketing Officer at NYUAD Art Gallery. Grube shares how he experienced Candidate Weekend at Sama Tower and witnessed the Saadiyat campus construction. He also shares that interacting with upper class students who had lived in Sama Tower enabled him to get to know and navigate around Abu Dhabi better. The multicultural setting and academic interdisciplinarity offered at NYUAD changed Grube's perspective on what it means to be a global leader and assisted him throughout his journey as a Music and Theater program double major student, and as Art Gallery Community Engagement and Marketing officer. Grube is now looking to continue his journey as an artist who brings artistic sensibilities into business context
  - Interview session with Judi Olson (Theater Program) and Lauren Kata (01:44:44), 04 July 2022; ADRG023_084 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_084)
    Video-recorded session with Judi Olson, Instructor of Costume Design and Arts and Humanities Representative on the Academic Staff Committee of Staff Council at NYUAD, recorded on Monday, July 4th, 2022, and facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Librarian for Archives and Special Collections, NYUAD Library. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    Judi Olson graduated from NYU's Tisch School of the Arts in 2009 and joined NYU Abu Dhabi in 2012. Between 2012 and 2016, Olson worked part-time on theater productions and joined NYUAD full-time in 2016. During her first four years, she worked on multiple student productions such as The Ramayana, The Aeneid, A Dream Play, and The Odyssey. In this interview session, Olson talks about the fluidity of the theater program and the transient nature of NYUAD, as well as the challenges and accomplishments of the past six years. Olson also shares nostalgic memories of the brunch culture in Abu Dhabi as a tradition of the expat community in the UAE, and her participation in the Abu Dhabi Choral Group.
  - Interview session with Jennifer McGlennon (Early Graduate Programs) and Lauren Kata (01:51:11), 12 July 2022; ADRG023_085 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_085)
    Video-recorded session with Jennifer McGlennon, Former Vice Provost of NYUAD Graduate Programs, facilitated by Lauren Kata, Assistant Academic Librarian for Archives and Special Collections. Conducted as part of The Memory Project.
    Jennifer McGlennon provides a comprehensive overview of her role as the founding Assistant Vice Provost of Graduate Programs at NYU Abu Dhabi. She shares her background in academia and consulting, including her involvement in educational projects across Indonesia, Australia, and the UAE. McGlennon reflects on the cultural shifts she witnessed in the UAE, particularly in Dubai, where she previously spearheaded educational initiatives. The interview delves into the complexities of establishing graduate programs at NYUAD, highlighting negotiations with department chairs in New York and the challenges of harmonizing institutional cultures across NYU's diverse schools. McGlennon emphasizes the importance of aligning resources and policies to support the needs of PhD students and faculty members, navigating funding arrangements and support services for international scholars. Throughout the discussion, McGlennon underscores the collaborative efforts between NYUAD and stakeholders, including the UAE government and NYU's central administration. She discusses the role of strategic research projects in shaping academic offerings and fostering interdisciplinary collaborations, concluding by reflecting on NYUAD's evolution into a premier academic institution in the region.
- Office of Social Responsibility - Partner Interviews, OSR 10th Anniversary Project, 2021
  Twenty-one (21) audio recorded interviews conducted and recorded by PPPT researcher Laura Assanmal during the summer of 2021, she was a team member in the NYUAD Office of Social Responsibility, the project was part of a 10th anniversary reflection on contract colleagues who have been part of the NYUAD community for a decade or longer, and led to the editing and writing of a 10th anniversary OSR booklet.
  - Interview session with Hazel Lorena and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (38:38), 10 June 2021; ADRG023_045 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_045)
    Audio-recorded session with Hazel Lorena, recorded on [June 10, 2021] and facilitated by Laura Assanmal. Conducted as part of The Memory Project and as part of the Office of Social Responsibility's 10th Anniversary Book Project. The interview was conducted in-person. For the most part, there are only two people present at the interview site (the interviewer and interviewee), but at certain times, there are people passing by in the background.
    In this interview session, Hazel Lorena shares her experiences and talks about the happiness brought by working abroad and at NYUAD, as well as about the challenges she faces. Hazel Lorena has been working at NYUAD since August, 2010 as a Public Safety Officer via G4S. Before coming to NYUAD, she lived in Manila, Philippines. She obtained her Bachelor's degree in Hotel and Restaurant Management, and upon graduation, she worked at Unilab, a pharmaceutical company in the Philippines. She later joined an agency in order to work abroad. She was 23 when she came to work in the Middle East and at the time of the interview had been working for 19 years. Lorena has previously worked as a receptionist at Montgomerie Golf Club in Dubai, as a waitress at a restaurant in Qatar, and later joined the security team at NYUAD. She shares her memories of the first class of NYUAD at Sama Tower and adult education classes offered by the Office of Social Responsibility. Despite the challenges, Hazel Lorena is very glad to be a member of the NYUAD community and regards NYU as one big family.
  - Interview session with Serkalem Bekele Admasse and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (14:55), 8 June 2021; ADRG023_046 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_046)
    Audio-recorded Memory Project session with Public Safety (G4S) officer, Serkalem Bekele, recorded on the 8th of June, 2021, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, a PPTP student for the Office of Social Responsibility and conducted as part of OSR's 10-year project and The Memory Project. The interview was conducted in-person. For the most part, there are only two people present at the interview site (the interviewer and interviewee), but at certain times, there are people passing by in the background.
    In this interview, Serkalem Bekele, Public Safety (G4S) officer, shares her family story, work life, and her journey to NYUAD. She starts by talking about her home (Ethiopia), family, languages she speaks (Amharic, English, Arabic) and her education background (Computer Engineering). Then, she shares about her first arrival to the UAE back in 2005. She mentions about her jobs in different places like Dubai Mall, Abu Dhabi University, the British Embassy and finally in NYUAD. Serkalem also talks about the changes she has seen at NYUAD from a small downtown Sama Tower campus to a huge Saadiyat campus with growing numbers of students and staff over the years. She also added motivating words that during difficult times we should not only focus on problems but on solutions and resolve them. In the end, she appreciates the working environment and the opportunities (language and life-skills courses) provided by OSR for their holistic development.
  - Interview session with Fathia Omar and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (17:23), 8 June 2021; ADRG023_047 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_047)
    Audio-recorded session with Fathia Omar, Controlling Supervisor, recorded on Tuesday, June 8, 2021, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 Year Project/Memory Project Partnership. The interview took place on the ground floor of C2, in front of the Office for Social Responsibility in NYU Abu Dhabi. There are two people present at the interview site - the interviewer and interviewee. There is slight background noise at 03:35, perhaps from Fathia's co-workers.
    Fathia describes her work in the camera control room and the role of a supervisor in the Security Office; her origin story of Berbera, Somalia, and the UAE; her language skills: Somali, English, Arabic, and her education, which was in UAE government schools, allowing her to get immersed in the Arabic culture. Regarding her journey to NYU Abu Dhabi — a friend told her that G4S is hiring, and she started in Al Ain, but then got invited to join NYUAD in 2010, and got interviewed by Mr. Robert Titus and Ms. Norca Vincent, getting accepted in the end. She wanted to work at NYUAD because she wanted to become independent and responsible — the support from her family helped her along the way. What she likes about the NYUAD community is that she met wonderful, diverse people, but a challenge has been the separation from her family. Lastly, Fathia reflects on possible plans for the future, which for her are studying in medical school to become a phlebotomist.
  - Interview session with Yasir Ur Rehman and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (22:29), 9 June 2021; ADRG023_048 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_048)
    Audio-recorded Memory Project session with Yasir Ur Rehman, Control Room Operator in Public Safety Department, recorded on the 9th of June, 2021, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, a PPTP student for the Office of Social Responsibility and conducted as part of OSR's 10-year project and The Memory Project. The interview was recorded in-person on campus. It took place in the C2 building, outside the OSR's office.
    In this interview, Yasir Ur Rehman, Control Room Operator in Public Safety, shares his family background, life events, work life, and his journey to NYUAD. He starts by talking about his home in Islamabad, Pakistan, languages he speaks (Pothwari, Urdu, English, Arabic), and his education progression. He talks about his clerical job in the Ministry of Education (Islamabad). During that time, he was influenced by his cousin, so he applied for a G4S visa and moved to the UAE in 2005. He tells of his early struggles at his new workplace with long working hours and low salary, and poor accommodation. After a year, he returned to Pakistan for marriage and again came back to UAE in May 2008. One day, he heard about NYUAD, so he decided to apply and later got accepted. He marks it as one of the most successful events of his life. Yasir also explains about his day-to-day work at NYUAD- handling the public safety control room. Yasir happily shares about his family responsibility, love for his daughter, and expectations from his son. He repeatedly appreciates the caring and humble working environment and management of NYUAD.
  - Interview session with Jayaprakash Subramanian and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (11:35), 9 June 2021; ADRG023_049 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_049)
    Audio-recorded session with Jayaprakash Subramanian, Security Officer, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 Year Project/Memory Project Partnership. The location of the interview is C2 building, in front of the Office of Social Responsibility, NYUAD Saadiyat Campus.
    Jayaprakash describes his home in India, and how he comes from a farmer's family; he speaks Hindi and English. In 2008, he joined G4S, then two years later the company sent him on an interview at NYU Abu Dhabi, and he got the job in August, 2010. Before NYUAD, he had multiple jobs, working in New Delhi at a bakery, and an advertising agency. In his free time, he likes to cook, watch movies, and meet up with friends (although due to COVID he is limited in that regard). He has taken almost all OSR courses: Public Speaking, Intermediate English, Creative Writing, Excel Crash Course...He likes that he has become financially independent throughout his time at NYUAD, but he misses his family. He is looking forward to his daughter's graduation from high school and a continuation of a stable, secure life.
  - Interview session with Andrew Moriasi and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (21:10), 9 June 2021; ADRG023_050 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_050)
    Audio-recorded session with Andrew Moriasi, Security Officer, and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility (OSR) 10 year Project/Memory Project Partnership. The location of the interview is C2 building, in front of the Office of Social Responsibility, NYUAD Saadiyat Campus.
    Andrew came to the UAE in 2007 and found work as a Security Officer, but then shortly after got the opportunity to do an interview with NYU Abu Dhabi and got the job as a Security Officer, where he received training, but he did additional studying on his own - he went on Coursera and got certified in First Aid and Mental First Aid, as a way to help his friends in crisis situations. He received certification in Religious Tolerance as well. Andrew reveals that he obtained a degree in Food Science in his home country -- Kenya -- and managed to teach his colleagues how to cook.
    He discusses how NYUAD allowed him to become financially stable and contribute to his children's college education and that he manages to call them every day to hear how they are doing. When asked, he tells Laura about the OSR courses. Then, Andrew shares that he had COVID in April, 2020, and how he felt during that time (fear of the unknown, solace in friendship) and that he managed to recover in about two weeks. Lastly, he shares what he likes most about working at NYUAD.
  - Interview session with Lilia Espanola Francisco and Laura Assanmal (OSR) (23:01), 10 June 2021; ADRG023_051 (Box Electronic Records, Folder ADRG023_051)
    Audio-recorded session with Lilia Espanola Francisco, recorded on Thursday, June 10th, 2021 and facilitated by Laura Assanmal, PPTP student. Conducted as part of the Office of Social Responsibility NYUAD 10 Years book project, in partnership with The Memory Project.